# 嗨喽大家好
Hello everyone
# 我是王刚
I'm Wang Gang
# 今天跟大家介绍一下我们四川的这三种菜
Today I want to share with you these three types of vegetable native to Sichuan
# 这个太重了我拿下来一样一样的介绍
This tray is too heavy. Let me put it down and introduce them one by one
# 这个叫棒菜看起来像莴笋
This is called "Bang Cai" (literally "stick vegetable") and it looks like celtuce
# 一根（小的）的话大概有一斤多
(A small one) weighs about 1 Jin (500g)
# 大的有两三斤三四斤的也有
Some bigger ones can weigh around 2 to 4 Jin (1 to 2kg)_
# 长得有点像莴笋
It looks like celtuce
# 我们这个棒菜在四川来说产量非常地高
"Bang Cai" is a very high-yield vegetable in Sichuan
# 就是春节前后（登市）
(It appears on the market) around Chinese New Year
# 因为春节前后大家大鱼大肉吃多了
Because people are bored of eating so much fish and meat during Chinese New Year
# 然后这个把皮撕掉
After peeling the skin off,
# 用它来清煮或者说加一些腊味下去煮
we can steam it or make a stew with some Chinese cured meat
# 煮出来这个菜的口感很软
It turns soft after boiling
# 就是特别的鲜 汤比较鲜
and the soup is full of umami flavour
# 然后这个
Then this,
# 这个看起来有点棱棱角角的
which looks quite irregular,
# 在我们四川这个叫菱角菜
is called "Ling Jiao Cai" (literally "water chestnut vegetable")
# 我们本地话叫菱盖儿菜
In our dialect we call it "Ling Gai er Cai"
# 菱角菜
"Ling Jiao Cai"
# 同样的它这个也是一样把这个老的皮给它撕掉
Similarly we remove the skin by tearing it
# 吃法的话就比这个棒菜多一种吃法
but it has one more way to cook compared to "Bang Cai"
# 它可以用来凉拌也可以用来煮汤
We can use it to make salads and soups,
# 然后可以用来炖肉
or stew with meat
# 同样的是春节前后（登市）这个产量非常高
It also (appears on the market) around Chinese New Year and it's a very high-yield vegetable
# 我们这个菱角菜呢它其实还有一个做法
There is one more way to cook "Ling Jiao Cai"
# 就是跟（竹）笋干萝卜干一样
Like dried bamboo shoots and dried raddish,
# 直接切开切开了之后晒
we can cut it and sun dry it
# 晒成干的东西
until it's fully dried
# 然后我们吃的时候再拿出来泡
Soak it in water before cooking
# 把它（泡）发好了不管是用来炒也好 用来炖也好
and, after it rehydrates, we can either stir fry and stew it
# 或者是凉拌也好
or simply serve it cold as a salad
# 然后我们这个菜的话跟另外两样它比起来的话
Compared to the other two types of vegetables,
# 它的保存的周期就更加长
it has a longer shelf life,
# 可以放到几个月甚至一年都可以
around several months or even a year
# 下面这个菜
Now the next vegetable
# 跟大家介绍一下这个菜
Let me introduce it
# 这个菜在我们这里叫法比较多
It has several names
# 有一个比较好听的名字叫超生菜
One catchy name is "Chao Sheng Cai" (literally "too-many-babies vegetable")
# 为什么叫超生呢
Why is it called "Chao Sheng" (having too many babies)?
# 因为它这里一坨一坨一坨的
Because of those many large branches
# 也叫做儿菜
It's also called "Er Cai" (literally "sons vegetable")
# 就是说除了一根茎上来之外它像花瓣一样
Because those branches grow from a single stem, like petals of a flower
# 会朝四边发展出很多“儿子”出来
And those branches are like sons to the steam, expanding in different directions
# 所以叫做儿菜
Therefore, it's called "Er Cai"
# 我们本地叫这个菜叫南充菜
As a local, we call it "Nan Chong Cai"
# 这个同样的也是春节的时候（登市）产量非常地高
It also (appears on the market) around Chinese New Year and it's a very high-yield vegetable
# 这个的话比较小 这个都有三斤多
This small one weighs around 3 Jin (1.5kg)
# 然后大的话可以到七八斤 十多斤的也有
Bigger ones can weigh around 7 to 8 Jin (3.5-4kg), or even 10Jin (5kg).
# 因为比较实在嘛 长得比较实在
As it is not hollow,
# 基本上都是实心的
and it's almost solid inside (therefore weighs a lot)
# 种得也比较多
It is planted at many places
# 同样吃法也是可以用来炖菜
We can make a stew with it, same as the last two
# 然后把这个老的地方撕掉 切成片
Tear the skin off and slice the veggie into pieces
# 就像那个萝卜丝一样放点盐给它出一下水
Add some salt to draw water out, just as what we do with radish juliennes
# 然后再加辣椒啊红油啊盐啊白糖这些拌一下来吃
Then add some chillies, red oil (chilli oil) and white sugar to mix and eat
# 我们这个儿菜呢还有一个吃法就是
Another way to cook "Er Cai"
# 把这个上面的儿把它弄下来 弄下来做泡菜
is to cut off those branches and make pickled vegetables
# 就是像泡萝卜这些跳水菜
All those pickled vegetables, like pickled radish,
# 就是直接泡一下短时间就可以吃
can be prepared within a short amount of time
# 吃起来味道也很鲜
They are also full of umami flavour
# 比较好吃 而且比较脆
Yummy and crunchy
# 所以在我们四川这些东西都是非常常见的
Therefore those vegetables are quite common in Sichuan
# 可能说这个的话在外地还有人经常见到过
People may find this ("Bang Cai") at other places,
# 但这种东西的话只有在我们四川吃得比较多
but these ("Er Cai") are mainly consumed by those staying in Sichuan
# 因为它这个第一个是便宜
Because, firstly, they are cheap
# 第二个是产量高
And secondly, they are planted in large quantities
# 然后我们这里特别喜欢把它弄来煮汤来吃
We like to add them to soup
# 它的汤也比较鲜
to enhance the umami flavor
# 如果想吃得清淡一点的话就直接用来煮水
If you prefer mild tasting food, you can just boil them with water
# 用白开水煮
Boil with water
# 煮熟了之后弄点酱油蒜直接就可以蘸着吃
After that, you can simply dip them into some soy sauce with minced garlic and enjoy
# 这个也算是我们这边产量比较高的一个青菜
This ("Er Cai") counts as one of the high-yield leaf vegetables here
# 也算作是青菜
It counts as a type of leafy vegetable
# 但是这三种同样是属于芥菜科里面的
Those three types of vegetables are all classified in mustard Family,
# 但是长得完全不一样
but they look completely different
# 好啦 如果你们喜欢这个的话想了解更多的话
Ok. If you want to learn more about them
# 你们在评论里面可以跟我留言
you can leave comments down below
# 后面的话会考虑把它做成一个菜谱出来
I would consider to develop a recipe using these vegetables later on
# 好啦本期视频就到这里了
Alright, that's all for this episode
# 拜拜
Bye-bye